Since they IPO'd 6 weeks ago, SpaceX
stock has absolutely cratered. It's down
more than 50% from its all-time high,
and as we're recording [music] this, it
reached a new all-time low of $107
per share. So, the question on
everyone's mind is, [music]
is SpaceX done for? Was it massively
overpriced? Will this company make it?
Well, this might be a hot take, but I
think that the market is incredibly
wrong about SpaceX, and I think it's an
incredibly mispriced asset. Think about
it from two simple perspectives. In
order to get the best AI model out
there, you need the most energy. Where
do you get the most energy? From the
sun. In order to do that, you need
access to space, cheap access to space.
SpaceX is the only company that has the
advantage here, and they recently had
flight 13 for their new spaceship, which
was a massive success, and they launched
Starlink V3. It was an incredible test.
We're going to get into that. The bull
case and the bear case is going to be a
sobering take on Limitless, which is,
you know, unique for us, on why SpaceX
is a generational company.
>> The bull case is mostly determinant of
just the baddest technology that they
are producing now, and I think we're
going to talk about that a lot. In terms
of actual market sentiment, it's tough,
right? It's like the stock IPO'd, and it
was incredible. It went up to $225 per
share. That's over two and a quarter
trillion-dollar market cap, which, you
know, that's unreasonable. That is so
much money. The multiples on the returns
in terms of how much revenue they're
making are just astronomical. It doesn't
make sense. But, it's not just the like
public market that can't figure out how
to price this. There's a lot of values
from these privately held banks that are
trying to put price per share estimates
on it, and they still can't figure it
out either. I think this is the widest
distribution of what banks are kind of
valuing the company at. We have
Morningstar putting it at $63, and then
we have Morgan Stanley on their bull
case putting it at $600. And to me, that
signals that this company is mostly
misunderstood. People don't know how to
value it. They don't know how to value a
company that is planning to change the
world today. Because a lot of the value
is promised in the future, so how do you
trade that? What multiples does that
trade at? And maybe in order to better
understand that we could talk about the
real technology that they're building
that's going to get them to this
spectacular market cap. Because I could
be empathetic. I mean, if you bought
this a couple weeks ago at 225, it's
been a tough ride. I think we're here to
provide a little bit of reassurance that
like, hey, short-term unsure, but
long-term there's some really compelling
cases to be made for why Starship
or why SpaceX in general, there's going
to be a lot of star naming in this
episode, is a really spectacular company
and it has monopolies across the board
on things that other companies just
can't really compete on.
>> I think it's important to lay out the
bad case for SpaceX because we've been
incredibly bullish about Elon Musk and
all of his companies on this show. And
in fact, I think both of us bought the
IPO when it did IPO. So we're in it with
everyone. If you're an investor that
that bought that IPO, we're here with
you. We feel your pain. So let's walk
through the bad case. Well, I'm
definitely also on board with that.
We'll get to the bull case a little
later, but let's let's look at the bad
case. Let's see what the armchair
critics are saying online, the I told
you so's, okay? So there's a few things
happening right now. Number one,
the fact that SpaceX was probably
massively overvalued. We know that Elon
Musk, in order to execute on his vision
of of turning civilization into a
Kardashev type one civilization, you
need a lot of money to do that. Space
travel is incredibly expensive. So he
tried to raise as much money as he can.
That's what he eventually did. The
market is now showing us that it wants
to kind of reprice it to what it's
actually valued at. And so it IPO'd at
$135. It's now sitting at an all-time
low at $107. I think as we're looking at
our screens right now, it's at like $111
at the time of recording. But another
big critic is only 4% of the share
supply was revealed or made available
for everyone. That is out of I think
it's around 16 billion shares. And I
think another 1 billion worth of shares
gets unlocked in about a week's time,
August 6th, I believe, which is 2 days
after their first quarterly report. So,
there's a lot of things going on here.
People are are like speculating, is the
Q3 report going to be very good or is it
going to be bad? Well, if you look at
their financial statements from 2025,
it's kind of sobering. They took a net
loss of I think $4.5 billion.
The Grok models, as we know, hasn't been
able to keep up with the frontier until
recently. With Grok 4.5, we have a lot
of information on that going forward as
part of our bull case. But, the point is
there is a very low float, and if the
stock price isn't able to keep up and
maintain its high price on a small
float, how do we expect it to do it on a
large float? For the rest of the year, I
think something crazy like 56% of the
rest of the stock supply is aiming to be
unlocked, and you need purchases to be
able to support that. So, we understand
the bear take, but there is also a lot
of good things that are expected for
this company. And as we said on our bull
case episode around the SpaceX IPO, this
is a long-term investment. If you
believe that space travel, harnessing
the sun's energy, training AI models on
infinite energy is incredibly important.
If you believe that robotics, if you
believe that, you know, Tesla and SpaceX
are going to have a merger eventually or
that they're synonymous companies run by
the same CEO, then you believe that
SpaceX is going to be a fundamental and
once-in-a-generation type company
10 years out from now.
>> In summary, I mean, SpaceX is trading at
about 80 times sales, which is
incredibly high. I mean, Palantir is the
next highest. Everyone freaks out about
that, trading at about 60 times. This is
a huge multiple on the future. Here is
the future that they're building. And
this is where I want to talk about the
kind of technical features of SpaceX as
a company. And there's four key pillars
that we could talk about here. One being
Starship, the second being Starlink, the
satellite network above our heads
currently flying right now. The third is
the AI opportunity, and the fourth is
their ability to manufacture physical
things better than everyone else. So,
maybe we should start with Starship
because Starship launch flight 13 just
happened last week and it was glorious.
Starship, for those who are not aware,
this is the Mars rocket. This is the
moon rocket. Now, it's mostly known as
the lunar rocket because the plan is to
get a Martian base, get a mass driver, a
lot of sci-fi stuff. But, to bring it
back down to what just happened.
Basically, 470-ft skyscraper went into
space. This was their 16th attempt and
it actually worked about as well as it
could have been. So, there's a few
things that they're testing for each one
of these launches. The first is the
ability to actually get the rocket into
space, which clearly it did very well.
The second is to land both of the
objects back on Earth. Those went well.
We'll talk about that in a second. And
the third is the ability to actually
distribute payload into orbit. And for
the first time ever, that went well with
real production hardware. So, we've seen
these Starship launches before. We've
got the Starship into space and it's
distributed They use this thing called
the Pez dispenser, which is a funny way
of just kind of distributing these
Starlink satellites. One thing
noteworthy about this is for the first
time ever, Starship launched active
Starlink version 3 satellites into
space. These weren't dummy units. They
were actual real pieces of hardware that
are now connected to the Starlink
network and have all of the capabilities
of direct-to-cell and much more
bandwidth than we're used to with
traditionally with these Starlink
terminals.
The other thing that it did really well
and that we're watching on this launch
video right here is that it actually
landed back on the ocean softly for the
first time. You'll notice that it landed
so soft that the rocket actually didn't
explode. It was It was incredible and
it's been floating there. I think it was
floating there for like over 2 days,
almost 3 days, just floating around in
the ocean because it landed so softly it
didn't blow up. And then there's the
booster, which we've seen them land
before a few times on those arms. It
didn't do that this time. That wasn't in
the test, but it had a pretty decent
landing to the point where they'll be
able to test that again. So, this launch
went about as good as it could have
been. You'll notice the heat shields on
this video that we're seeing, that did
well. A big part about re-entry when
you're rapidly deploying these rockets
is making sure that you can rapidly
deploy these rockets, and a big part of
that is protecting your rocket ship from
the re-entry burn. The ship is going
like at many times the speed of sound
through a very dense atmosphere, and it
causes a lot of heat. You'll notice that
from flight 10 all the way on the left
to flight 13 all the way on the right,
that heat shield is doing really well.
So, all the signs are pointing towards
rapid reusability coming up quickly. So
much so that the next Starship launch
flight, they're going to test the
landing of the actual ship. So, we're
going to get a video probably of the
ship actually landing back on those
chopstick arms, and I think that's going
to be spectacular. So, everything so far
is working fairly well. My major
takeaway from this is the technology is
so far advanced at SpaceX for spaceship
flight at least versus any other
company. I think their nearest
competitor is Jeff Bezos' Blue Origin
that it like Elon is just in a field of
his own right now. But, I think what a
lot of the market and investors are
thinking right now is I don't see how
this materially impacts my life today.
So, why should I care about this? How do
I price in what these rockets are
eventually going to bring to me? I don't
have that kind of an effect on myself
right now in my day-to-day life, and I
think that's probably a fair take, but
it's also in that very same sense a
mispriced take. I mean, look at this
thing. This thing is like larger that
we're launching things that are larger
than Statue of Liberty for reference
here, right? And then we're putting like
thrusters on these things, 33 Raptors,
and we're just sending these things with
a massive payloads. I think it's like
5,000 tons into space to release these
Starlink satellites. I think it released
20 V3 Starlink satellites, which is more
broadband connectivity than Starlink has
had in its previous generation. So, it's
just insane how much power and
innovation is in these actual things.
That being said, it's an expensive
endeavor, and there is a high error
rate. But if there's one man to pull it
off, it's Elon and he's repeatedly shown
this with his other companies at Tesla
and he's done this at SpaceX for over 20
years now. So, is the market mispricing
this asset? Yes, potentially. But also,
this is over a long-term time horizon
type of thing. If you're investing in
this and you're looking at this for over
like say like a 6-week period, this is
probably not the right kind of asset to
invest in. This is a long-time thing and
and this is something that I have
personally have a lot of conviction on.
But one thing to mention about this
company is it's not just about SpaceX
anymore. It's not just about space in
any kind of material sense. It is about
AI and a number of different other
things. So, as we know, um SpaceX and
xAI merged about I think a couple of
months ago pre-IPO and they are
currently in ownership of all the Grok
models. And Grok actually came out with
a new model 4.5 recently. And while Grok
4.5 isn't necessarily a frontier model,
it is about 80 to 90% of a frontier
model and it's incredibly cheap and it's
very fast to use. And in this current
world where a lot of enterprises are
spending tens to hundreds of millions of
dollars on AI every single year, they're
looking at ways to cut down costs and
Grok 4.5 is a really good way to do
that. But the second major thing is Elon
has built one of the largest compute
clusters for GPUs better than anyone and
everyone and he's aggressively expanding
it. He announced I think Colossus 4 a
few weeks ago. Now, the reason why this
is important is the scaling laws haven't
changed. More compute equals better AI
models. So, if you are Mark Zuckerberg
or if you're Elon Musk who are who have
the largest data centers right now, you
have a good shot of taking on the likes
of Anthropic and OpenAI at some point.
And this is shown in the model release
cadence. So, we have Grok 4.5 right now,
but in 2 weeks time as of this
recording, you're going to have Grok
4.7. And then 2 weeks after that, you're
going to have Grok 5. And each of these
models are successfully much larger than
its predecessor, which means it's more
intelligent and more effective and
arguably could catch up to the very
capable fable and mythos models that
come from Anthropic and GPT-5.6 that
comes from OpenAI right now. So, that's
another major business unit. And the
final thing is the fact that when you
have all this compute, what's the best
thing to do with it if you're not
training your own models? It's selling
it to other businesses. And SpaceX has
indirectly become one of the largest
near clouds out there to the tune of, I
think it's like they're selling $60
worth of compute over the next, I think,
9 to 12 months. Anthropic is one of
their largest purchases, paying them
$1.25 billion
per month. So, the point is whilst it
might be losing money right now, whilst
space travel might be a very expensive
business, it has all these other
business units which are looking to be
incredibly profitable in the near
future, and I don't think people are
pricing that in.
>> Yeah, the iterative nature of SpaceX is,
I think, something that only people who
observe it on a regular basis witness.
And from the people who aren't there on
the outside, it just looks like these
products don't really change or evolve
much. But when you see them on a per
product basis, how quickly they iterate
and how strongly they grow, uh it's
really amazing. When you think about the
Raptor engines, the engines that power
Starship, from version 1 to version 3,
uh the efficiency has gone 2 to 3x every
single time. The cost has gone
absolutely ridiculous in terms of the
downward direction. This happens with
the Starlink terminal satellites. Like
you mentioned, each of these every one
of these version 3s is equivalent to 20
times that of a version 2. Same thing
happened with their Starlink terminal,
they're now on version 5. The new
version is 60% more efficient. And all
of these increases compound in a way
that adds a tremendous amount of value
to each one of these verticals. In the
case of the AI argument, the AI pillar
of this company, I mean, you mentioned
that no one's really able to build as
fast as they are and iterate again as
fast as they do. They built that
Colossus data center in what, 160
something days, which is like many, many
hundreds of days faster than any other
company can. Yeah, by a long shot. And
the next one's going up even faster. And
the iterative nature of their ability to
build hard hardware products is I think
one of the most compelling values and it
gets kind of into that fourth pillar
manufacturing, where a company who's
able to move atoms in an organized way
efficiently and effectively is so much
more valuable than a company that isn't
because we've gotten good over the last
20 years at building software really
well. And when you think about the most
valuable companies in the world, a lot
of it revolves around their ability to
create software. I mean, look at all the
AI labs we talked about on a daily
basis. Not a single one of them has
released any compelling pieces of
hardware. It's all just been bits on a
screen and it's really difficult to
manage supply chains and move these
things around. And that's why we see
companies like Anthropic, companies like
Google going to SpaceX and asking them
like, "Hey, could you give us some of
that compute? We don't quite know how to
build it as fast as you do, but we'd
love to use it." And SpaceX is the
company that can do that. And in fact,
if SpaceX was just an AI company, it
would be the most remarkable AI company
in the world because of its ability to
manufacture data centers at scale and to
do the things required to do so.
Remember the episode we filmed a few
weeks ago or even last week, I think it
was, where Elon personally purchased a
billion dollars' worth of power just so
he could plug in a Colossus data center
and get that online faster. And their
ability to do that at scale is something
that's really compelling and highly
competitive because they can build
anything. And when you think about what
comes down the line for these companies,
you think about in the case of Tesla, we
have Cybercabin, Optimus. And there is
certainly a world in which these two
companies can emerge. We see a lot of
the crossover happening where now
Cybercabs are equipped with Starlink
terminals. And Starship is using the
cold-rolled stainless steel that is used
in Cybertruck. And all of this this hard
physical labor is really going into
creating a really compelling company, a
really compelling manufacturing story, I
think, more than anything else. And
doing so all mostly domestically. There
has been this battle to move things back
here to the United States. And
everything that these companies make is
right here on US soil and it's they just
do an amazing job of doing it.
>> I do think to a certain degree you have
to be sort of crazy or delusional to
believe in the vision that SpaceX and
any Elon Musk company is pitching out
there at the time.
>> It's crazy.
>> It is crazy. It's quite out there and
like I don't blame you for for critics
that I see in the comments for a lot of
our videos where we talk about SpaceX in
particular. They're like, you know, you
know, this guy's crazy. Like he's not
going to be able to pull this off. And
you know, as a normal sensible person
would agree with you. But one thing I
will say is if you do believe that this
vision is able to be executed upon
whether it's Elon but mostly his team
that does all the like a lot of the hard
work, then you can feasibly put an
investment thesis against not just
SpaceX but any Elon company. Like I I I
think about it like this. If you
purchase SpaceX stock, right? You're
basically buying what is it? A space
launch company,
a telecom company, you are buying
a GPU data center, and you're also
buying a frontier AI lab. All of that
comes packaged in one. And if all all of
it has to work. If all of it if one
thing doesn't work, then kind of like
the thesis gets broken. But then there's
also this other company called Tesla
which is now like a frontier robotics
company. It's not just a car company,
right? And so what do these robots
eventually need? They need some form of
a brain to guide them to to scale them
in a mass production type of way. Well,
you have Grok models which are trained
on a ton of experimental physical data.
And you know, Elon Musk is working on
that separately. So at some point you
see a lot of synonymous kind of cohesion
between these two companies. So you have
to be delusional. Now, to kind of like
ground ourselves a bit, there is a lot
of bearish events if you want to
categorize it like that happening over
the next 6 months until the end of this
year. The main one in my opinion is the
supply unlock. If you have 56%
of the entire supply for shares for
SpaceX getting unlocked by the end of
the year, the big question everyone's
mind is, is there enough money to even
support the current valuation that they
had that there is, or should I just wait
and see
for all of these shares to become
unlocked, let the price find an actual
you know, price that the market thinks
is is valuable and that makes sense, and
then buy later on
you know, when that price is hit. Now,
we we don't do investment advice here.
We just kind of like talk about what our
general thesis will be, but let's look
at some other companies that were in a
similar position almost a decade ago. If
you look at Meta, when they IPO'd I
believe in 2012, their stock price went
below IPO price for about a year, and
since then it's gone on a meteoric rise.
The same thing can be said of Uber over
short over a shorter timeline, privately
held. So, the point is, companies aren't
always fairly priced. I think Elon Musk
raised a ton of money to be able to
execute on this gargantuan envision that
he has, and the market is now pricing it
more fairly. Um, keep an eye on the
supply unlocks. The first one is going
to be August 7th, two days after their
first-ever quarterly earnings. I'm
curious in this quarterly earnings
whether they actually turned towards
profitability in some forms of ways. I'm
going to look at the individual business
units, perhaps Grok specifically, and
yeah, I guess we'll we'll see where we
go from there. But right now, I'm a
long-term believer in this company. I
believe there's only one person that's
able to execute and pull this off, and I
believe Elon is that moonshot better.
>> You just, you know what else I'm bullish
on? It's this company called Ledger, and
thank you to Ledger for sponsoring this
part of the episode, where if you are
building with AI agents, you're worried
about security, and an agent with
unchecked access is a pretty brilliant,
but probabilistic teammate with access
to important secrets. So, Ledger Agent
Stack fixes that with four open-source
tools. DMK skills and CLIs for Ledger
Wallet, Ledger Enterprise, and Ledger
Enterprise multisig that lets your agent
work with crypto while you stay in full
control. Tell your agent, you can
rebalance my wallet ETH to 40%, fastest
swaps, it does the math, drafts the
swaps, and then stops. The transaction
lands on your ledger signer, and nothing
moves until you approve it. Agents
propose, humans approve, ledger's signer
enforces. And the coolest thing for me
is this works with cloud code, code X,
cursor, and it's all open source, ready
today on developers.ledger.com. You can
find a link in the description below.
Thank you to Ledger for supporting our
show. And I want to finish the bullish
case for Starship with the manufacturing
story again one more time. Just talking
about how quick they're actually going
to make this reality happen cuz EJ, you
did kind of humble us a little bit. This
is a sci-fi future that seems
impossible. This seems like something
you would read in a book more so than
witness it with your own eyes. I've seen
it happen with Tesla before. I haven't
driven a car in a couple of years. Like
the Model Y is the best-selling car in
the world. They've done Mission
Impossible before. This is not anything
new to them. And I see a very clear case
in which they could do it again. When
you look at Starship, for example, do
you know how long it takes to build a
Starship now? It's two weeks.
>> Two weeks
long.
>> And they're simultaneously building
seven of them at once. Is that for
Starship number 41? Yes, this is
Starship version three, dude.
>> Ships 41 through 48 are in simultaneous
production. So, they're building seven
of these at once. They're building one
every 14 days currently. And that
pipeline is going to be increasing
significantly. So, for this year in
2026, Gwynne Shotwell, the COO, the like
godsend of SpaceX, basically the
effective CEO of SpaceX is saying
they're planning to launch one Starship
every single month. In 2027, they're
planning to launch 1 to 400 Starships
in the year.
So, the cadence is going to increase
significantly. And the way it works is
it's it's unbelievable. It's like these
rolls of steel go in, and then a 400-ft
rocket just rolls out after a couple of
days. And they're going to be doing this
over and over. And as they do, the
Starlink capabilities are going to
multiply 20-fold per launch. And all of
these things kind of compound in a way
that again is that iterative improvement
and a compounding on itself in a way
that is so incredibly compelling and you
could see how this is going to happen
across the company with data centers.
The first one took 160-something days.
The second one's going to take 100. The
third one's going to take 50. They're
just going to continue to iterate their
way down and before you know it they
have this like unbelievable ability to
manufacture these very complicated
things at scale. So, that's kind of what
I'm looking for and when I look at
these, it's very difficult to value
something on an exponential curve
because of how slow that initial
exponential is before it kicks up. And
then once it does kick up, over the
matter of a couple of months it could
change the entire look and feel of a
business and we saw this with Tesla in
2018 where it took a very long time.
Tesla for the people who weren't around,
it was the most shorted stock in the
market for years and it had the highest
short float of any company in the world
and then over one year it went up like
10x and it very aggressively repriced
because people realized, "Hey, they
actually are going to manufacture the
most popular car in the world and figure
out the self-driving thing." We're
probably going to see something like
that happen with SpaceX. It probably
takes a long time because I mean like
you said, there's a lot of bearish
signals that they will have to get
through first if you are a short-term
trader. If you're someone who's
interested in the share price this year
or next year, this might be a bumpy
ride. I mean because there is a stat
that I read that I was like, "Oh, that
sucks." In the case of IPOs in general,
the last 15 largest US IPOs since 2006
over the last 20 years have averaged
drawing down 50% since the IPO and have
averaged finishing the year down 33%
where they go public. So, there is no
precedent for strong IPOs really in this
case. It has a valuation problem where
it's trading at 80 times trailing sales.
Profit is non-existent. There's a long
way for it to go, but if you believe in
this future, it is an incredibly
compelling version in which this company
is worth more than many other of the top
companies combined. It just takes a long
time and and it's hard and it's going to
be a really difficult battle, but it is
possible. And if you're a long-term
investor, that's that's kind of the
thing to to hold on to. It's a big
vision, but Elon has proven time and
again that he is an amazing zero-to-one
physical infrastructure scale, and
that's exactly the opportunity that
SpaceX presents, albeit at a very
ambitious vision. If you think about it,
I think in the optimistic timeline, the
SpaceX shuttle business itself could pay
for the entire company, right? If you
think about its vision of putting AI
satellites out there to train models on
infinite amounts of energy from the sun.
Anthropic will want that. OpenAI will
want
will eventually want that, and there's
only kind of like one highway to get
there in the cheapest, most
cost-efficient way, and that would be
through SpaceX. But again, it's a bet on
whether they are able to pull it off.
When it comes to the stock price in
general, even if you are skeptical on
the stock price, if you're a bullish
person about this, there is a silver
lining where it's like, "Okay, well, if
the supply unlock comes on later this
year, maybe there's a better way to get
access to this, and maybe you just kind
of like wait patiently for them to be
able to pull this off. But one thing is
for sure, Elon is kind of hell-bent on
making this a reality, and time will
tell whether this is something that is
going to pay off. Again, you need a lot
of time to figure this stuff out, and AI
is probably the most mispriced asset in
general because no one knows what any of
this is going to any of this is going to
do. But the point of the the kind of
like mispriced valuation that we're
seeing right now is there's not enough
market to uphold these prices. You've
got the Anthropic, OpenAI IPOs coming on
later this year. So, we're going to need
even more money for that. And I think a
big precursor to SpaceX going up in
price in general will be does AI create
enough GDP value across the entire
globe? And that is a question mark,
albeit a small one, because it's
impacting so many sectors at the same
time. So, we'll get more clarity over
time. But again, once clarity is
achieved, you're kind of like a little
bit late to to that eventual trade. So,
I understand the bear case, I understand
the bull case, but one thing is going to
be for sure, Josh and I are going to be
up 24/7 racking our brains around this
thing until we we figure it out and
we'll be reporting on it live on this
show every single week. So, I think that
brings us to the end of this episode.
Thank you so much for listening. This
was an incredibly exciting episode to do
because, you know, we were kind of going
against some of our bull cases that we
had of the previous one that we had
around SpaceX. But, thank you so much
for listening. If you listen to this on
YouTube and you want to subscribe,
what's happening? Please leave us a
comment, subscribe, turn on
notifications, helps us out massively.
If you listen to us on Spotify or Apple
Music or any way that you're listening
to us, please leave us a comment or give
us a rating, it helps us out hugely. Um,
but I think that's it. Is there anything
else, Josh?
>> Yeah, no, it's just it's exciting. Like
Star This company feels very very easy
to understand if you if you read sci-fi
books and you understand the future and
you're like, "Oh, man, this is This is
the only company in the world that kind
of makes makes me feel
a certain way when I go out and watch
these launches. And there's like no one
trying to capture and build the future
like they are. So, it's exciting. And I
don't know if it's going to work. It's a
really ambitious project. So, by betting
on the company, you're kind of betting
on this really uncertain future, but
hey, it's a lot more exciting if it does
work than if it doesn't. And I think
that's what I'm most excited about. So,
yeah, like you said, thank you all so
much for watching. [music] Don't forget
to share it with a friend who might also
enjoy. And yeah, we'll see you guys in
the next episode.
>> [music]
[music]